The Evil of the Daleks(Episode 2)
《Daleks 的邪恶》 (第二部分)
Doctor Who (1963) 04x09b
原为《神秘博士》老版第四季第九集
【时间轴/翻译】巴蛮子sz
基于 opentitles.org 英文字幕翻译
（注意：此字幕的时间轴按2021动画重制版重新调整）
Sincro: wyxchari
DALEK: Who are you?
你是谁
DALEK: Answer!
回答
- JAMIE: I don't know what are you being so cautious...?
- DOCTOR: Ssh!
- 不知道你这么谨慎是为了...  - 嘘!
JAMIE: They left the door open for us, didn't they?
他们给我们留门了, 对不
- JAMIE: It's half past the nine o'clock.
- DOCTOR: Yes, I know.
- 这才9点半呢  - 是的, 我知道
JAMIE: They made the appointment for ten. Why have we come early?
他们约的时间是10点, 我们提前来干什么?
DOCTOR: The early bird catches the worm, Jamie.
早起的鸟儿有虫吃, Jamie
DOCTOR: Now, do be quiet, there's a good chap.
现在, 别出声, 好小伙
DOCTOR: And for heaven's sake, don't knock into anything.
还有千万别撞上任何东西
DOCTOR: Ssh!
嘘!
JAMIE: Any good, this?
有什么发现吗
DOCTOR: It's interesting.
这很有意思
DOCTOR: In fact, Jamie, it's quite remarkable.
事实上, Jamie, 这很令人吃惊
JAMIE: You told me outside it said "Genuine Victorian Antiques".
在外面时你说这是“维多利亚真品古董”
JAMIE: All the stuff in here is brand new!
这里所有的东西都是新的!
- DOCTOR: You noticed that.
- JAMIE: Of course I did. The man's a rogue.
- 你注意到啦  - 那当然. 这人是个大盗
DOCTOR: Yes, so it seems.
是的, 看来很像
- DOCTOR: Except...
- JAMIE: Except what?
- 除非...  - 除非什么?
DOCTOR: Except that all these things are not reproductions.
除非这些都不是重新制作的
- DOCTOR: They're all genuine.  -JAMIE: That's ridiculous!\
- 它们都是真品  - 那太荒谬了
DOCTOR: Hey, look at this.
嘿, 看看这个
DOCTOR: "To one deed box, four guineas. "
契税箱一个, 支出四基尼
(几尼金币法定? ?
DOCTOR: This is a bill from William Deering and Son. 1866.
这是一张记账单, 属于 William Deering and Son, 1866年
JAMIE: Then it's a forgery.
那么它是伪造的
DOCTOR: If you were going to make a forgery,
wouldn't you dirty it up a bit?
如果你要伪造一个东西, 你不会来点做旧什么的?
DOCTOR: Yellow the edges, crinkle it up? This is brand-new.
把边缘搞成黄色, 把它弄皱一点? 这张是新的
- JAMIE: I've got an idea.   - DOCTOR: What?
- 我有个想法 - 什么
- JAMIE: All the stuff in here is genuine...   - DOCTOR: Yes.
- 这里所有东西都是真的...  - 嗯
- JAMIE: .. but brand-new. - DOCTOR: Well done.
- 但都是新的 - 说得不错
JAMIE: That is impossible, unless...
但这是不可能的, 除非...
JAMIE: Waterfield could have invented a time machine, like the TARDIS
Waterfield 可能发明了一架时间机器, 就像TARDIS
JAMIE: and he's bringing this stuff back from Victorian times.
然后他从维多利亚时期带回了这东西
DOCTOR: It's not very likely, is it?
这不太可能, 对吧
DOCTOR: But the only way to find out is to ask Waterfield.
不过唯一能搞明白办法, 是去问这位 Waterfield
WATERFIELD: Kennedy!
是 Kennedy!
WATERFIELD: What happened?
什么情况?
DALEK: The human discovered our communication system.
这个人发现了我们的通讯系统
- WATERFIELD: And you murdered him?
- DALEK: He would have betrayed us.
- 然后你就杀了他?   - 他很可能出卖我们
- WATERFIELD: You don't have to kill!
- DALEK: Silence!
- 你没必要要他的命啊!  - 闭嘴!
WATERFIELD: I won't be silent! What are you dragging me into?
我才不闭嘴! 你都把我拖到什么事里面了啊?
WATERFIELD: You destroyed a human life. Don't you understand that?
你夺走了一个人的生命, 你明白吗?
- DALEK: That is of no consequence.
- WATERFIELD: No consequence?
- 这并没有什么后果 - 没有后果?
DALEK: There is only one form of life that matters.
唯一重要的就只有一种生命形式
DALEK: Dalek life.
Dalek 的生命
DALEK: Obey your orders, Waterfield!
服从命令, Waterfield!
WATERFIELD: No, wait! What am I to do with the body?
不, 等等! 我拿这尸体怎么办?
WATERFIELD: I can't...
我不能...
WATERFIELD: I can't go on with this.
我不能再继续下去了
DOCTOR: I'm sure I heard somebody shouting.
我确定我听到有人在喊叫
- DOCTOR: We've got to get in.
- JAMIE: What about the wire?
- 我们得进去 - 用这个线试试
DOCTOR: It's too pliable.
这太软了
PERRY: Oh! What are you doing here?
噢, 你们在这里干什么?
- DOCTOR: You made the appointment!
- PERRY: For ten o'clock.
- 你约我们来的啊   - 说的是10点
DOCTOR: We thought we'd be early. What are you doing here?
我觉得应该早点来. 你在这里干什么?
- PERRY: I work here.
- JAMIE: Then what are you creeping about for?
- 我在这里工作啊  - 那你怎么鬼鬼祟祟的?
DOCTOR: I think you've got some explaining to do, Mr Kenneth Perry!
我觉得有些事情你得解释一下, Kenneth Perry先生!
PERRY: My name isn't Kenneth. It's Keith.
我的名字不是 Kenneth, 而是 Keith
PERRY: Look, I don't understand this.
你看, 我没搞懂
DOCTOR: It's Keith... Do you know a man called Bob Hall?
是 Keith ? 那你认识一个叫做 Bob Hall 的人吗?
PERRY: He's a man Mr Waterfield employs.
他是 Waterfield 先生雇佣的一个人
DOCTOR: He keeps some very rough company, including a man called Ken.
他有些不怎么样的同伙, 其中有一个叫做 Ken
PERRY: Ken? Kennedy!
Ken? 是 Kennedy 吧
DOCTOR: What? What do you know about Kennedy?
什么!  你都知道Kennedy 些什么?
PERRY: Wait a minute. This is all too quick.
等一下, 咱们别这么快
PERRY: I'll answer your questions if you'll answer mine.
如果你先回答我的问题, 我就回答你们的
PERRY: This old police box was for a collector of curios.
这个警察亭是给一个收藏家准备的
- DOCTOR: But it belongs to me!
- PERRY: Why is it so important to you?
- 但它是我的!  - 为什么它对你这么重要?
DOCTOR: Because... because of what's inside it,
and because it happens to be my property.
因为它里面的东西, 因为它碰巧是我的财产
- JAMIE: Where is it?  - PERRY: At the back.
- 它在哪儿?  - 就在后面
DOCTOR: Is there another way through, this door is locked.
那还有别的路过去吗? 这个门锁住了
PERRY: We might be able to get over the yard gates.
我们得先通过院门
PERRY: You see, this door has an electric lock on it.
但你看, 这门上有一个电子锁
DOCTOR: You're going to show me where this yard is.
你要给我们指一下你说的院子在哪里
PERRY: I say, if it's a police box, shouldn't we get the police?
我说, 如果说这是一个警察亭, 我们是不是应该叫警察来?
JAMIE: Doctor!
博士!
PERRY: That's Kennedy!
那是 Kennedy!
DOCTOR: He's dead!
他死了!
- DOCTOR: What are you doing?  - PERRY: Getting the police.
- 你要干什么?    - 叫警察
PERRY: Don't touch anything. I'll be as quick as I can.
别碰任何东西, 我尽量快点
- JAMIE: Should we have let him go?
- DOCTOR: He's doing the right thing.
- 我们该让他走吗?  - 他做得对
AMIE: But the Tardis!
但是 TARDIS 呢?
DOCTOR: We'll have to find it before he comes back.
我们必须在他回来之前找到它
DOCTOR: I wonder what this telephone interference is.
我很好奇这电话干扰是怎么回事
JAMIE: Looks as if Waterfield's cleared out.
看起来 Waterfield 早跑掉了
DOCTOR: Why make an appointment to see us at ten?
他为什么要约我们在10点见面呢?
JAMIE: Obviousely he didn't know
he was going to have a fight with Kennedy.
显然他并不知道他会跟Kennedy 起争执
JAMIE: Oh, come on Doctor, let's find the Tardis and go!
得了, 博士, 我们还是找到TARDIS 离开吧
DOCTOR: Yes, the Tardis...
是的, 找TARDIS
DOCTOR: How did he die?
他是怎么死的
DOCTOR: His limbs are stiff, his hands clenched..
他四肢僵硬, 双手紧握
DOCTOR: He died in horrible agony. Look at his face.
他死的时候很痛苦, 看他的脸
- DOCTOR: Hello... - JAMIE: What?
- 咦?    - 什么?
- JAMIE: It's your picture! - DOCTOR: Yes.
- 是你的照片    - 是的
DOCTOR: Now, he fell like that, with his arm stretched out.
看, 他的姿势好像是要去够什么东西
DOCTOR: Jamie, go out into the hall,
and measure the length of it up to the door here.
Jamie, 你到大厅去, 量一下那里到这个门的距离
- JAMIE: 14... 15.
- DOCTOR: It's only five from the door to the wall.
- 14...15   - 从门到墙这里只有5步
DOCTOR: There must be another room behind here.
这后面肯定还有一个房间
JAMIE: Hey, Doctor! There's a keyhole.
嘿, 博士! 这里有个锁孔
DOCTOR: You're right. Waterfield will have the key.
你说得对, Waterfield 应该有钥匙
DOCTOR: We'd better find something to prise it open with.
我们最好找个什么东西把它撬开
DOCTOR: Well...
好了...
DOCTOR: Look at this.
看看这个
DOCTOR: That's where your telephone interference is coming from.
电话干扰就是从这里来的
DOCTOR: This is interesting.
这很有意思
- JAMIE: Hey! The other half of your picture!  - DOCTOR: Yes.
- 嘿! 你照片的另一半!    - 是啊
DOCTOR: Don't open that!
别打开那个!
PERRY: This way. Along here.
这边, 在这里
PERRY: Here we are.
就这里了
PERRY: That's funny... There were a couple of other gentlemen here.
奇怪...刚才这里还有两个人呢
PERRY: They seem to have... disappeared.
他们好像是...消失了
MOLLIE: Hello, sir.
你好, 先生
MOLLIE: Are you feeling better?
你感觉好点了吗
MOLLIE: Oh, you did have a party last night, didn't you, sir!
哦, 你昨晚肯定参加聚会了, 对不
- MOLLIE: The master sent this in for you.
- DOCTOR: The master?
- 主人要我把这个送进来   - 主人?
- DOCTOR: Mr Waterfield?
- MOLLIE: No, sir. Mr Maxtible.
- Waterfield 先生吗?   - 不, 先生. 是 Maxtible 先生
MOLLIE: Mr Waterfield came back from abroad last night, sir,
with you and the young gentleman.
Waterfield 先生昨晚才回来, 先生, 跟你和那位年轻绅士一起的
- MOLLIE: Don't you remember?
- DOCTOR: Not very well, no.
- 你不记得了吗?  - 记不太清了
DOCTOR: Ooh!
噢!
MOLLIE: I'd best not wake him.
我最好不要吵醒他
- DOCTOR: What's your name?
- MOLLIE: Mollie Dawson, sir.
- 你叫什么名字   - 我叫 Mollie Dawson, 先生
DOCTOR: This stuff works remarkably quickly.
这东西见效很快啊
- MOLLIE: Am I to pour some more?   - DOCTOR: No, thank you, Mollie,
- 要我再倒一点吗  - 不了, 谢谢你, Mollie
DOCTOR: but you can tell me what the date is.
不过你可以跟我说说今天日期是什么
MOLLIE: The date?
日期?
DOCTOR: Yes, I am feeling very much better,
是的, 我现在感觉好多了
DOCTOR: but I don't seem to be able to
remember the date and where I am.
但我好像想不起来日期, 也想不起来我在哪儿了
MAXTIBLE: Mollie, that will do.
Mollie, 这样就行了
MAXTIBLE: The answers you require, sir,
might come better from me.
你想要的答案, 先生, 可能最好由我来给
MAXTIBLE: My name is Theodore Maxtible,
and I am the owner of this house.
我的名字是 Theodore Maxtible, 我是这个房子的主人
MAXTIBLE: Pray don't get up.
请不要起来
MAXTIBLE: I have the greatest sympathy for your condition
我对你的处境深表同情
MAXTIBLE: since I was the cause of it.
因为都是因我而起的
DOCTOR: And this is Mr Edward Waterfield, I presume.
而这位, 我猜是 Edward Waterfield 先生
DOCTOR: You don't keep appointments, do you?
你从不守约, 对吧?
- WATERFIELD: There were circumstances.   - DOCTOR: Yes, there were!
- 出了些状况  - 是啊, 有状况!
MAXTIBLE: Please, Doctor. First things first.
拜托, 博士, 先说重要的事情
MAXTIBLE: You asked what date it was and where you were.
你刚才问你在何时何地
DOCTOR: Yes. Well?
是的, 怎样?
MAXTIBLE: You're in my house, some miles from Canterbury.
你在我的房子里, 离坎特伯雷只有几里路
（注：坎特伯雷：英国英格兰东南部的市鎮, 离伦敦有几十公里）
MAXTIBLE: The date is June 2nd 1866.
当前日期是1866年6月2号
DOCTOR: What do you think you're up to? You steal my property,
你知道你们在做什么吗? 你们偷了我的东西
DOCTOR: You spirit Jamie and me 100 years back in time
你们迷倒了Jamie 和我, 弄到了100年以前
DOCTOR: and you murder a man along the way.
你们顺道还谋杀了一个人
WATERFIELD: We had nothing to do with the death of that man.
我们跟那个人的死没有关系
- DOCTOR: I don't believe you.   - MAXTIBLE: You will believe, Doctor.
- 我不相信你  - 你会相信的, 博士
MAXTIBLE: All of us are victims of a higher power.
我们都是受害者, 有一股强大的力量
MAXTIBLE: A power more evil and terrible
than the human brain can imagine.
一股邪恶而可怕的力量, 远超出人类所能想象
DOCTOR: Power? Victims? What do you mean?
力量? 受害者? 你什么意思?
- WATERFIELD: They've taken my daughter Victoria.
- DOCTOR: Who are they?
- 他们抓走了我女儿 Victoria  - 他们是谁?
MAXTIBLE: You will not be kept in suspense very much longer, Doctor.
你很快就会知道了, 博士
MAXTIBLE: Pray come with us, and we will show you how it all began.
请跟我们来吧, 我们跟你说明一下这一切是怎么开始的
WATERFIELD: Doctor, do whatever it is that they ask. I beg of you.
博士, 不管他们要求你做什么, 你都照做吧, 我求你了
WATERFIELD: My daughter's life is in your hands.
我女儿的性命在你的手上
DOCTOR: I will listen. I promise.
我会仔细听, 我保证
DOCTOR: Is er... Is that your daughter?
那个...那是你的女儿?
WATERFIELD: No, sir. That is a painting of my wife as a young girl.
不, 先生, 那画的是我的妻子, 她年轻的时候
WATERFIELD: She is dead now, rest her soul,
but Victoria is the image of her.
她已经去世了, 愿她安息. 不过 Victoria 长得很像她
DALEK: You have not eaten.
你还没有吃饭
DALEK: You will eat. That is an order.
你得吃, 这是命令
- DALEK: Answer!  - VICTORIA: Yes.
- 回答!  - 是
DALEK: You will not feed the flying pests outside.
你不得喂食外面的飞鸟
DALEK: Answer!
回答
VICTORIA: Yes.
是
DALEK: Move to the machine.
到机器那里去
DALEK: Move!
去
VICTORIA: No.
不
DALEK: Move!
走!
DALEK: The weight of your body has fallen by 17 ounces.
你的体重下降了17盎司
VICTORIA: What do you expect?
你还能指望怎么样?
VICTORIA: What do you expect? For pity's sake, let me go!
你还能指望怎么样?  可怜可怜我, 放我走吧!
DALEK: Speak when you are told to speak!
让你说话的时候再说话
DALEK: More food will come.
还有更多食物会送过来
DALEK: Eat it, or you will be fed by force!
吃了它, 否则你会被强制喂食!
MAXTIBLE: Here we are, Doctor. This is hallowed ground.
我们走吧, 博士. 这里地方比较神圣
MAXTIBLE: Here we shall not be disturbed by the servants.
在这里我们不会有仆人来打扰
DOCTOR: Yes, very impressive.
嗯, 挺不错
DOCTOR: Now perhaps you'll explain what all this is about?
现在也许你可以解释一下都是怎么回事了?
- MAXTIBLE: Patience, my dear sir, a little longer.
- DOCTOR: Patience?!
- 稍安勿躁, 亲爱的先生  - 稍安勿躁?
DOCTOR: You don't seem to understand what's happened.
A man has been murdered!
你们好像还没搞懂发生了什么? 都有个人被杀了!
DOCTOR: You behave as if we're going on a Sunday School outing.
你还弄得好像我们要去学校组织的周日郊游似的
MAXTIBLE: Neither Waterfield nor I were responsible for his death. Cigar?
他的死不是 Waterfield 的错, 也不是我的错. 来根烟?
DOCTOR: Why have you brought us here?
你为什么带我们来这里?
DOCTOR: Who are these enemies of yours,
these ones you say control you?
你们的敌人是谁?  你说在控制你们的人?
- MAXTIBLE: Brilliant minds, Doctor.
- WATERFIELD: They are monsters!
- 高智商的头脑, 博士  - 他们都是怪物
MAXTIBLE: Oh, I admit, Waterfield, they have behaved callously.
哦, 我得承认, Waterfield, 他们做事情很冷血
WATERFIELD: Inhuman monsters!
没有人性的怪物!
- DOCTOR: Inhuman?
- WATERFIELD: Creations of the devil!
- 没有人性?   - 是邪恶的缔造者!
- MAXTIBLE: Let me explain.
- DOCTOR: Please do!
- 我来解释一下    - 赶紧的
MAXTIBLE: I've always been fascinated
by the concept of travelling through time.
我一直都对时间旅行这个事情很着迷
MAXTIBLE: Waterfield here is an expert in certain technical matters,
这位 Waterfield 先生在技术方面是一位专家
MAXTIBLE: and I have the money to indulge my whims.
我也有点钱可以砸在自己的古怪想法上
MAXTIBLE: Everything you see about you was constructed by us two.
你在这里看到的所有东西都是我们俩建造的
- DOCTOR: To try to find a way of exploring time?
- MAXTIBLE: Yes.
- 为了找到穿越时间的方法?   - 是的
MAXTIBLE: Now, this is my theory.
好了, 现在说说我的理论
- MAXTIBLE: A mirror reflects an image, does it not?
- DOCTOR: Yes.
- 一面镜子可以反射图像, 对不?   - 可以
MAXTIBLE: So, you may be standing there
and yet appear to be standing 50 feet away.
所以, 你可以站在这里, 但又好像出现在50英尺之外
MAXTIBLE: Following the new investigations 12 years ago
by J Clark Maxwell into electromagnetism,
基于麦克斯韦在12年前在电磁场方面的研究
MAXTIBLE: and the experiments by Faraday into static electricity...
以及法拉第的静电实验...
- DOCTOR: Static?   - MAXTIBLE: Correct.
- 静电?     - 正确
MAXTIBLE: .. Waterfield and I first attempted
to define the image in the mirror,
...Waterfield 和我试验了在镜子中固定图像
MAXTIBLE: and then to project it.
然后再投射出去
MAXTIBLE: In here, Doctor, are 144 separate mirrors.
这里, 博士, 有144面镜子
WATERFIELD: Each is of polished metal. Each is subjected
to electric charges, all positive.
每一面都是金属抛光制成的, 还会充上电, 全都是正电
MAXTIBLE: Like repels like in electricity, Doctor,
正如电负荷会同性相斥, 博士
MAXTIBLE: and so we attempted to repel the image
in the mirrors wherever we directed.
于是我们尝试了在镜子间反射图像, 以让它到达我们期望的地方
- DOCTOR: You mentioned static electricity...
- WATERFIELD: That was our last experiment.
- 你刚才提到了静电...   - 那是我们最后一个实验
WATERFIELD: Negative and positive electricity
had failed, so we tried static.
负电与正电都失败了, 所以我们尝试了静电
- WATERFIELD: If only we had know the powers we'd unleash.
- DOCTOR: Powers?
- 可惜我们没能早点知道, 我们会释放出什么样的力量   - 力量?
WATERFIELD: In the middle of our final test with static,
creatures burst out of the cabinet,
在我们最后一次静电实验中, 有种怪物从柜子里面蹦出来了
WATERFIELD: invaded the house and took away my daughter.
入侵了我们的房子, 掳走了我的女儿
MAXTIBLE: Oh, my dear fellow! My dear, dear fellow!
哦, 我亲爱的朋友, 可怜的家伙 !
MAXTIBLE: We shall win through, now that the Doctor is here.
既然博士现在来了, 我们应该能赢了
DOCTOR: These creatures...
这些怪物...
WATERFIELD: We had opened the way for them with our experiments.
是我们的实验给他们打开了大门
WATERFIELD: They forced me into the horror of time travel.
他们强迫我进行时间旅行
WATERFIELD: They ordered me to steal a box belonging to you
他们命令我去偷你的那个亭子
WATERFIELD: and thus lure you into a trap and transport you here,
以钓你上钩, 再把你们传输过来
WATERFIELD: ...to get you with your colleague Mr McCrimmon.
以抓住你和你的朋友 McCrimmon 先生
- DOCTOR: They knew about me?   - MAXTIBLE: They gave us likenesses.
- 他们认识我?     - 他们给了我们详细描述
WATERFIELD: What could I do? They said my daughter would die.
我能怎么办?  他们说否则我的女儿就得死
- DOCTOR: What are they called, these creatures?
- DALEK: Doctor!
- 他们叫什么名字, 这些怪物?   - 博士!
DALEK: Now do you understand?
现在你明白了吧?
DOCTOR: Oh, yes. Perfectly.
哦, 是的, 完全明白
DOCTOR: Move back!
退后!
DOCTOR: Our plan has worked.
我们的计划成功了
- DALEK: We shall triumph! You will obey!
- DOCTOR: Obey? What do you want?
- 我们会胜利! 你将服从!   - 服从? 你想要怎样?
DALEK: We have your time ship. We will destroy it
我们得到了你的时间飞船, 我们将销毁它
DALEK: ...unless you help the Daleks with an experiment.
...除非你帮 Dalek 完成一项实验
DOCTOR: What experiment?
什么实验?
DALEK: You will help us test another human being.
你得帮我们测试另外一个人类
- DOCTOR: What sort of test?   - DALEK: No questions!
- 什么样的测试?   - 不许问
- DOCTOR: I won't be your slave!   - MAXTIBLE: Doctor, I beg you...
- 我可不会做你的奴隶!   - 博士, 我求你了...
DALEK: No harm will come to you if you agree.
如果你同意的话, 就不会受到伤害
DALEK: Where is your companion?
你的同伴在那里?
- DOCTOR: Jamie?   - WATERFIELD: He is in the house.
- Jamie?   - 他在房子里
WATERFIELD: I have done everything you asked me to.
你们让我干的事情, 我全都干了
DOCTOR: Why do you ask about Jamie?
你为什么问起 Jamie?
DALEK: He is the human being who is to be tested.
他就是我们要实验的对象
- DOCTOR: What do you mean? Tested how?   - DALEK: Silence!
- 你什么意思? 怎么实验?   - 闭嘴!
DALEK: You will reveal nothing to your companion.
你不得向你的同伴透露任何情况
DALEK: Obey the Daleks! You are in our power!
服从 Daleks 的命令! 你在我们的手上!
DOCTOR: What have you done with your infernal meddling?
你们到底插手干了些什么邪恶勾当?
DOCTOR: What is this test?
实验内容是什么?
- DOCTOR: Do either of you know?
- WATERFIELD: No.
- 你们俩谁知道吗?    - 不知道
MAXTIBLE: I believe I do.
我想我知道
MAXTIBLE: They, I mean the Daleks, tell me
they've always been defeated by human beings.
他们, 我是说 Daleks, 跟我说他们一直被人类打败
DOCTOR: In the long run, yes.
从长远来看, 是的
MAXTIBLE: Possibly because of some factor possessed by humans
可能是因为人类所具有的某些特质导致的
- MAXTIBLE: that is absent in Daleks?
- DOCTOR: Possibly.
- 而 Daleks 缺这些特质  - 有可能
MAXTIBLE: Perhaps they want to find out what it is,
and transplant it into their race?
也许他们想搞明白到底是什么东西, 然后嫁接到他们这个种族上
WATERFIELD: But if they do do that, they ally this with
their own alien intelligence, they'll be invincible!
他们要是这样做了, 跟他们的外星智能联合起来, 他们就所向无敌了!
WATERFIELD: Maxtible, you should have...
Maxtible, 你早就应该...
MAXTIBLE: My dear fellow, I am merely surmising.
I know nothing definite.
亲爱的朋友, 我也只是猜测. 我也不是太确定
MAXTIBLE: Besides, what could we have done,
even if I had known for certain?
再说了, 就算我确实知道, 我又能做什么呢?
MAXTIBLE: The fact was, nay, is, they hold your daughter Victoria.
事实是, 他们关押了你的女儿 Victoria
DOCTOR: And now they've got Jamie.
现在他们又抓了 Jamie
MOLLIE: I'm sorry, sir. I didn't mean to wake you.
对不起, 先生, 我不是故意吵醒你的
JAMIE: It's not funny.
这不好笑
MOLLIE: The master left this for you to drink, sir.
主人把这个留给你喝的, 先生
MOLLIE: This'll clear away the cobwebs.
他可以让你清醒一点
MOLLIE: Here you are, sir.
给你, 先生
JAMIE: Where's the Doctor?
博士在哪儿?
- MOLLIE: He's with the master and Mr Waterfield.
- JAMIE: Waterfield?
- 他正跟主人和 Waterfield 先生在一起  - Waterfield?
- RUTH: What are you doing here?
- MOLLIE: Just seeing to the young gentleman, miss.
- 你在这里干什么?   - 刚过来看一下这位年轻的男士, 小姐
RUTH: Go and bring some tea.
去, 端点茶来
RUTH: Well, go along.
诶, 快去啊
- RUTH: Please, Mr McCrimmon.
- JAMIE: You know my name?
- 请坐, McCrimmon 先生  - 你知道我的名字?
RUTH: My father told me that you and your friend
arrived last night, with Mr Waterfield.
我父亲告诉我说您和您的朋友昨晚到了, 跟 Waterfield 先生一起
JAMIE: Your father? I'm sorry I seem to have
great difficulty in remembering anything.
您父亲?  很抱歉, 我好像什么事情都很难想起来
RUTH: He owns this house. I'm his daughter, Ruth Maxtible.
这栋房子是他的. 我是他的女儿, Ruth Maxtible
JAMIE: How do you do? Have you seen the Doctor this morning?
很高兴认识你. 你今天早上见到博士了吗?
RUTH: He's talking with my father. He'll be along presently.
他跟我父亲在一起谈话, 很快就会过来
RUTH: Do you have everything you need?
您还有什么需要吗?
JAMIE: I don't know what this stuff is, but it seems to work all right.
不知道这个东西是什么, 但它好像很有用
- RUTH: Mollie shall bring you some tea.
- JAMIE: I'm obliged to you.
- Mollie 会给你端点茶过来的  - 我很感激
- JAMIE: Oh, Miss Maxtible.
- RUTH: Yes?
- Maxtible 小姐  - 什么?
JAMIE: Could you tell me who that is in the portrait?
你能告诉我这张画里面是谁吗?
RUTH: That's a portrait of Mr Waterfield's late wife.
那画的是 Waterfield 已过世的妻子
- JAMIE: She is very lovely.
- RUTH: Yes, and his daughter looks just like her.
- 她很漂亮  - 是的, 她女儿跟她一模一样
- RUTH: You're quite comfortable?
- JAMIE: Yes, thank you.
- 请自便   - 好的, 谢谢你
JAMIE: 1866.
JAMIE: So that's what Waterfield's done.
原来这就是 Waterfield 干的好事
MOLLIE: Here we are, sir. I've been as quick as I could.
来了, 先生. 我尽可能快了
MOLLIE: Shall I pour for you?
要我给你倒吗?
MOLLIE: Poor young gentleman.
They shouldn't have given you so much to drink.
可怜的年轻人, 他们不应该让你喝那么多酒的
- WATERFIELD: Doctor... I do ask you to consider.
- DOCTOR: I have made up my mind.
- 博士... 我真的请求你再考虑一下  - 我已经决定了
WATERFIELD: But they ordered you not to tell your friend anything.
但他们命令你不要告诉你朋友任何事
DOCTOR: Do you think I will allow Jamie
to run into danger? No, I will not.
你觉得我会让 Jamie 陷入危险吗? 不, 我不会的
- WATERFIELD: Suppose he refuses to do what they want?
- DOCTOR: We shall see.
- 假设他拒绝干呢?   - 看情况吧
DOCTOR: He's still asleep.
他还在睡
DOCTOR: The gas in that box of yours was pretty potent.
你那盒子里面的气体效果很强啊
WATERFIELD: It was Maxtible's invention.
那是 Maxtible 的发明
- DOCTOR: Jamie...
- WATERFIELD: Mollie!
DALEK: Order the Doctor to begin the test.
命令博士开始实验
MAXTIBLE: But I must first explain to him what he has to do.
但我必须得先跟他解释清楚要他干什么
DALEK: Go now. Obey the Daleks!
现在就去, 服从 Daleks 的命令
WATERFIELD: But your friend is vital to the plan of these Daleks.
Absolutely essential.
但你的朋友对于这些个 Daleks 的计划很关键, 绝对重要
DOCTOR: So it seems. So who could have kidnapped him?
看来是. 可能是谁绑架了他?
WATERFIELD: Oh, why won't you understand?
The threats they make are not idle ones.
哦, 你怎么就不明白, 他们的警告可不只是说说而已的
WATERFIELD: Kennedy was murdered.
Kennedy 就被杀死了
WATERFIELD: Without your friend, our only hope is gone...
没有你的朋友, 我们唯一的期望就没有了
WATERFIELD: unless... unless you know something.
除非... 除非你知道些什么
WATERFIELD: You seem to be well acquainted with the creatures.
你似乎对这些怪物很熟悉
DOCTOR: Everything you say, Waterfield, is true.
Waterfield, 所有你刚才说的, 都是真的
DOCTOR: If we cannot find Jamie
如果我们找不到 Jamie
DOCTOR: the Daleks will take pleasure in killing everyone in sight,
这些 Daleks 会很乐意杀死所见到的每一个人
DOCTOR: and their greatest pleasure will be in killing me.
而让他们最高兴的事情, 是杀死我
DALEK 1: The humans have been told to begin the test.
已经通知人类开始实验
DALEK 2: Any delay will result in death.
有任何拖延都将处死
DALEK 2:There will be no delay!
不允许有拖延!